やだな　受験
I hate exams.
小テスト　だるい
I need to do this right.
ちゃんとしなきゃ
Hurry up, I want to play already!
ムカつく　はやく遊びてー
勉強　勉強
Study, study!
なんだあいつ１人だけチャラついて
I hope she at least reaches an average score...
せめて平均点くらいは
She's just acting all cool by herself.
No one cares about a loser like you.
お前みたいのかまってる暇はねえし
What's wrong with her?
何なのよ　あの子
She should just stay in the nurse's office.
ずっと保健室にいればいいのに
She gets special treatments just because she can't attend classes...
ちょっと不登校になれば特別扱いしてくれるもんね
Another supplementary class, huh...
また補習かよ
自分があんなカーで来ちゃって
It would be great if she got kicked out because of this.
これでリスカでもしたら最強じゃねぇ
You're really annoying.
マジうざい
Help me...
助けて
Help me, God!
助けて神様
5 Yen
That wish,
その願い　この夜トが確かに聞き届けた
5 Yen
has been clearly heard by me, Yato!
Hey, this Ayakashi's really big, isn't it?
って　なんか大きくないですか　このあやかし
It's exam season,
受験前だしな　ピリピリしてるんだろ
so everyone's on edge.
It will be fine as long as you're here.
お前がいれば　大丈夫だ
行くぞ　伴音
Let's go, Tomone.
Yes, Yato-san.
はい　夜トさん
Come, Hanki!
こい　伴器
Partner
ほーらほらほらほらほら
豊葦原の中津国
I beseech you, all sacred things that dwell within this blade,
荒び足らせぬ「彼」のものよ
allow me to pass judgment, and cleanse all manner of rotten impurity!
伴器を以って砕かせる
種々の障り穢れを打ち払わん
Rend!
斬
You're not even a worthy playmate for my Sacred Tool.
神器の遊び種にもなりゃしねえ
夜トさん
Yato-san? Hey, Yato-san!
ちょっと　夜トさん
Oh, right!
Return, Tomone.
戻れ　伴
The smell of your sweaty hands is just awful!
手汗　最悪
おおおお前　主に向かって
How dare you say that to your master!
夜トさん　お話があります
Yato-san, we need to talk.
Huh?
I want to quit being your Sacred Tool.
私　夜トさんの神器辞めます
Huh? Wait, Tomone.
いや　伴音
It's been only three months—
俺達まだ３ヶ月…
もうだめ　もう無理　もう限界
I can't stand it anymore! It's impossible. I'm at my limit!
社の一つも持てないマイナー神と放浪生活なんて
I can't stand a nomadic life without a shrine like this anymore!
生理的に　いや
Every single part of my body can't take it anymore!
Um... I should be the one crying...
あの　泣きたいのはこっち
わ…分かった　分かったから
Okay, okay, I get it!
伴器　お前を放つ
Hanki, I release you.
Yup, it's finally gone.
消えた　消えた
餞別として言っとくがな
Let me tell you this as a parting gift.
辞める時は一ヶ月前に申請
It's common sense to give a full month's notice before you actually quit!
これ常識
ご親切にどうも
Thank you very much, you homeless, unemployed man with jersey who calls himself a god!
住所不定無職の自分は神で　というジャージーの人
Damn you, so that's your real reason!
テメェ　それが本心か
くそ　俺がうれてから泣きついても知らねーからな
Damn it! Don't come crying back to me when I make it big, understand?!
今に一億二千万の信者を引き連れて
I will claim all 120 million believers and stand atop of all other gods!
あらゆる神の天辺に立ってやる
ぼけが
You fools!
Noragami
Hatsuyuki Presents
In one hand, I grasp a loaded gun.
弾丸込めた小銃を僕は片手に持っている
Here I come as fast as I can, as you shiver.
震えた君の居る場所へ　足を早め向かっている
Tick tock, tick tock, go the hands of the clock.
（チクタク針をチクタクと）
It only urges my trembling heart.
焦る心を急かしただけ
Tick tock, tick tock, go the hands of the clock.
（チクタク針をチクタクと）
It keeps pounding incessantly.
留まる気配もなく進んでゆく
Tick tock, tick tock, go the hands of the clock.
（チクタク針をチクタクと）
At the edge of the beginning and the end.
終わりと始まりの境目
Tick tock, tick tock, go the hands of the clock.
（チクタク針をチクタクと）
Everything's overlapping again.
全て重なった
Hey！どうして僕は待っていた
Hey!
What was I waiting for?
Hey！どうして僕は待っていた
Hey!
Alone in a dimly-lit room.
薄暗い部屋一人きり
Hey!
Hey！どうして僕は待っていた
What was I waiting for?
Hey!
Hey！どうして僕は待っていた
For that sound, as the door is kicked open.
ドアを蹴破るその音を
Hey!
Hey！どうして僕は待っていた
What was I waiting for?
Hey!
Hey！どうして僕は待っていた
Alone in a dimly-lit room.
薄暗い部屋一人きり
Hey!
Hey！どうして僕は待っていた
What was I waiting for?
Hey!
Hey！どうして僕は待っていた
There's nothing left to fear.
もう恐れることは無いよ
I grasp a loaded gun.
弾丸込めた小銃を持って
I kicked open that door bound ever so tight.
固く閉ざされたドアを蹴破った
I fire that gun,
吸い付いた銃口が跳ねて
and blow away, the me I was yesterday.
昨日の僕を貫いた
The sadness overwhelms me, I embrace it.
上澄みそう絶望を受け取って
明日へと僕は歩き始めた
And I start on my way 'til tomorrow.
また今夜待ち合わせよう
Let's rendezvous tonight.
Oil-based
本字幕由诸神字幕组(kamigami.org)制作，仅供交流学习，禁止用于任何商业用途
日听:小然&千夜  翻译:maki&迩祢  校对:木落&叶隐  时间轴:Gissa  压制:久嘉
Yato All Year Round!
All your
Stupid Tomone, I can't believe she'd actually quit on me.
Sigh... That's better.
くそ　伴音の奴
There's no way I could erect a decent shrine with just this...
本当に神器辞めるとは
Or rather, I must find another Sacred Tool, fast!
Yato All Year Round!
All your problems will be solved!
やれやれ　どっこいしょ
Even if I'm a god, I'm pretty much unarmed without a Sacred Tool- no, naked!
これっぽちじゃ　お社立てらんねーなぁ
I can't take on any requests like this!
つか　社の前に新しい神器見つけねーと
いくら神の俺とて
Well, requests themselves rarely come anyways.
神器なしじゃ　丸腰同然
つか　丸裸だっつの
こんなんじゃ　依頼が来ても
Yes, thank you for your patronage!
I deliver quick, safe and sound! Yato, at your service!
ま　依頼自体が滅多に来ねーがな
Huh?
Milord is missing?
Episode 1
A Housecat, a Stray God, and a Tail
はい　ご指名ありがとうございます
早くて安くて安心　デリバリーゴッドの夜トでございます
Kamiisha Station
ウエサマ
Milord?
There really are people who name their cat like this.
Name:
Milord
Searching for a Lost Cat
Last seen leaving the house on November 2 at 6:00 PM.
Did not return home; family is worried. It might be
awkward calling his name but if you find him,
please contact us.
Tel: 03-0000-0000
Ono
いるよね　ペットにこういう名前つけちゃう人
ウエサマが行方不明
殿様　王様　神様とか
Yeah, like "Milord," "King," or "God."
神様
God...
あみだって　犬に痛い名前つけてんじゃん
Didn't you name your dog "God" after the leader of Zenith, Ami?
ぜニーズのリーダーの
痛いって何よ
What do you mean by that? Shiina-kun is my bride!
椎名くんは私の嫁
私は断然百鬼夜行だなぁ
I'm a complete fan of Hyakki-Yakou.
Ｖ系のどこがいいの
What's so good about that visual-kei band?
Milord! Milord!
ウエサマ
そっちこそ　ぜニのどこがいいんだよ
What's so great about Zenith?
ウエサマ
ぜニは神なんだから
Because Zenith is a god!
神は断然百鬼夜行
If you're talking "God", then it's definitely Hyakki-Yakou!
Hey, Milord!
ウエサマよ～い
ちょっとひより
Which one do you think is better?!
あんたはどっちが神だと思う
神のダンロード終わった
I finished downloading my god!
さあ　世紀の決戦はファイナルラウンドに縺れ込みました
And now, we're back in to the final round!
お互いに間合いを取って
Both are watching each other closely and...
おっと　足を掴まれてしまった
Oh my! He got his legs!
どうする　蟷野
What will Touno do?
He did it!
やった
There he goes with his Jungle Savate technique!
決まった　必殺ジャングル・ソバット
ごめん　あんたに聞いた私達がバカだった
Sorry, we're the stupid ones for asking you.
ひよりは隠れ格闘技ファンだったね
Hiyori is a secret fan of martial arts, after all.
これは隠れてるっていうのかな
Can you really call this a secret?
親には言ってないんでしょう
You haven't told your parents, right?
この趣味知ったら　お母様はきっと卒倒なさると思う
I think my mom would freak out if she found out about my hobby...
なんて野蛮な
ウエサマ　ウエサマ
Milord!
"How barbaric!"
壱岐家の名に恥じぬような立派な淑女になりなさい
"Forget about all that, and focus your efforts on becoming a lady...
Milord!
ウエサマ どちらに御座せられますか
Milord, where are you?!
そして　いずれは立派な婿君を
and bag yourself a wonderful groom!"
ウエサマ
Milord!
もう　何で2人どもお母様の口癖知ってるの
How do you know what my mom sounds like?!
でもさ　ひより
But really, Hiyori, are there other guys you like besides Touno?
あんた　蟷野以外に好きな男いないの
そうそう
That's right! Like one that's within your reach!
もっと身近で婿君になりそうなさ
好きな人　ね
Someone I like, huh...
好きな人なんて
Someone I like...
ウエサマ
Milord!
Hey! Wait!
おい　こら
待て
Don't run, Milord! Hey!
逃げんなって　ウエサマ
おい
ひより
Hiyori!
いや
No!
おい　どうした
Hey, what happened?!
女の子が飛び出したぞ
A young girl just suddenly ran out!
危ないじゃないですか 急に飛び出すなんて
That's dangerous!
Running out like that so suddenly!
What if you had died?!
死んだらどうするんです
いや
Rather than that, you...
それより　お前
Hiyori!
ひより　ひより
しっかりしろ　ひより
Hang in there, Hiyori!
Hiyori!
ひより
ちょっと　大丈夫
Are you all right?!
今　救急車を呼んだ
I've called an ambulance just now!
Huh?
Huh?!
What?!
ひより　聞こえる
Hiyori, can you hear me?!
ひより
Hiyori!
Thank goodness! You woke up!
よかった　目を覚ました
大丈夫　どこか痛む
Are you all right?
Does it hurt anywhere?
あなた　はやく見てあげて
My dear, hurry up and examine her!
R-Right!
Yes, she seems fine.
大丈夫そうだ
よかった
Thank goodness!
お父様
Father.
ＣＴも問題なかった
It seems there's nothing wrong with your CT scan either.
脳波も正常だよ
Your brainwaves are normal as well.
You only suffered minor scratches, even though you got hit by a bus.
バスに撥ねられたっていうのに　かすり傷で済むなんて
バスに
A bus...
あなた　心配だわ
I'm worried, dear.
ひよりの大切な体に何があったら
If something happens to her precious body...
Iki General Hospital
うちの病院なんですから　しばらく入院させたら
Since it's our hospital, how about we keep her hospitalized here for a while?
Iki General Hospital
お前ね
Hey, there are other patients waiting to be admitted too, you know...
Iki General Hospital
空き屋を待ってる患者さんもいるんだぞ
But...
でも
私と一緒にひかれた男の人は
What about the other man who got hit?
おお　いた
Ah, I saw him! I think?
いたような
えっ　そんな人いなかったよ
Eh?
There wasn't anyone like that.
気づいたら　もうひよりが倒れてて
By the time we noticed, Hiyori was already collapsed on the ground.
あれ
Huh?
ひより　まだ意識がはっきりしないのかな
I wonder if Hiyori's consciousness is still unclear...
But he was there...
でも　いたの
眠いのね　疲れてるんだわ
Are you sleepy?
You must be exhausted. Get some more rest.
今日はもう休みなさい
確かに　男の人がいたの
There was a man back there.
それに　あの時
Besides, I remember seeing another me lying on the road at the time...
私がもう一人いたような
まだ生きていたい
I still want to live!
あの子はどこ
あいつに遺産はやらんぞ
あの子に会いたい
I want to meet him.
何時になったらここから出られる
When can I finally leave this place?
お母さん
Mommy.
うそつき　うそつき
It hurts, it hurts!
痛い　痛いよ
この待ちでは　多分
あなた　元気になったら遊びに連れていってね
We'll play outside when you get better, all right?
何　この声
What... are these voices...
息　息が苦しい
痛い　痛いよ
すごく遊びたいよ
仕方がない
Can you hear the voices from Nirvana?
彼岸の声が聞こえるのか
そんだけ動けりゃ　大丈夫か
You must be fine if you can move that much.
You're that guy from this morning!
あなた　今朝の
あん時はどうも
Thanks for saving me!
ま　本来ならあの車は避けられたが
Well, I could have avoided that vehicle without your help, but...
俺を助けた人間なんか初めてだ
you're the first human to ever save me.
あ…あなた　誰
Who are you?!
私は神です
I'm a god.
もしもし　警察ですか
Hello, is this the police?
あの　自分のこと神とかいうジャージーの変な男が
Uh, there's a man in a jersey here, calling himself a god...
待て待て待て
Wait, wait, wait, wait!
俺は正真正銘八百万神の一人
I'm legitimately, genuinely one of the eight million gods!
夜ト神だ
I'm a Yatogami.
夜ト神
Yatogami?
I've never heard of such a god, not even once!
そんな神様聞いたことありません
ただの一度も
まあ　今はまだ絶賛売り出し中の宿無しだが
Well, I'm still a god that's starting out from scratch, but...
Just you watch, I will make my name so famous!
見てろ
すぐにこの名を轟かし
Me
皆が平伏し
Everyone will talk about me and love me. I shall become the God they desired!
我に乞い　願うような神になる
そして
And...
万歳　万歳
いずれこの国の天辺に
Someday, I shall stand atop of this country!
On stands: Yato
今夜も時化そうだな
Looks like tonight's going to be stormy.
ここは奴らの巣窟
This place is their den.
神器もいない今　長居は無用
I can't stay too long without any Sacred Tools.
野良も今夜は使用中だしな
It looks like we're in for rough weather tonight.
ちょっ　私のお見舞い
Hey, those are for me!
お前　名前は
You, what's your name?
ひより　壱岐ひより
Hiyori. Iki Hiyori.
ひより
Hiyori...
俺はお前の無事を見届けた
All right, I've made sure you're okay.
これでチャラな
Now we're even, okay?
See ya!
じゃな
Wai—
まっ
体が重い
My body feels heavy...
意識が
My consciousness... Yato...
夜 ト
Noragami
N
o
r
a
g
m
i
Hiyori!
ひより
N
o
r
a
Ami-chan, Yama-chan!
g
あみちゃん　やまちゃん
a
m
i
Are you okay now?
もう大丈夫なの
Yes.
I'm really glad you're fine now.
ったく　よかったよ　何ともなくて
Sorry to make you worry.
ごめんね　心配かけて
If you jump out like that again,
今度飛び出したりなんかしたら
I'll punish you with a Jungle Savate.
ジャングルソバットでお仕置きすんぞ
If it was done by Touno-sama,
蟷野さまにかけられるなら本望かも
it might be a reward instead.
What's that supposed to mean?
何それ
Hey, hey, Hiyori!
ちょっとちょっと　ひより
Sorry, I suddenly feel sleepy sometimes.
ごめん　なんか時々すごく眠くなって
Were you up all night playing video games?
徹夜でゲームでもしてたのか
I wonder if that day was a dream.
あれって　夢だったのかな
That day, I feel like I met someone that night...
あの日　夜の病室で
誰かに会ったような
Jersey...
ジャージー
Are you all right, Hiyori?
大丈夫　ひより
You seemed dizzy all day.
なんか今日一日ずっとふらふらしてっけど
Yeah, I feel really sleepy.
うん　なんかずっと眠くて
Maybe you slept too much at the hospital?
入院中寝すぎたんじゃない
It's right after the accident after all.
事故った後だしな
What's wrong, Hiyori?
どうした　ひより
Name:
Milord
Searching for a Lost Cat
Last seen leaving the house on November 2 at 6:00 PM.
Did not return home; family is worried. It might be
awkward calling his name but if you find him,
please contact us.
Tel: 03-0000-0000
Ono
Ah, the one from before.
ああ　この間の
That's right.
そうだ
I remember there was a guy in a jersey who chased after a cat.
確かこの猫を追いかけてた時も
ジャージーの人がいて
Milord!
ウエサマ
I'm sorry, you two. Go on without me.
ごめん二人とも　先帰ってて
I must go forth and search for Milord.
わたし
ウエサマを探さねばなりませぬ
Huh?!
Milord!
ウエサマ
Milord?
That's not him...
違うな
Milord!
ウエサマ
If I find that cat...
猫を見つければ
I might be able to remember.
ちゃんと思い出せるかもしれない
Milord!
ウエサマ
That drowsiness again...
また眠気が
This smell...
この匂い
Hey, Milord!
おい　ウエサマ
Come out! There's some catnip here!
ほら　木天蓼あんぞ
The storm's really brewing, huh...
本格的に時化てきやがったな
Milord!
ウエサマ　待て
Wait, don't move. Don't run away now...
動くな　逃げんなよ
What's wrong?
どうしたどうした
Smells good...
いい匂い
いい匂い…
Smells good...
Smells good!
いい匂い
These small fries... There are too many of them!
雑魚だが　数が多すぎる
There's no end to them if I faced them one by one!
相手してたら　切りがねぇ
Did you pull a prank against them?!
お前　あいつらからかっただろ
Milord... It seems you've been taking this too far!
ウエサマ　ご戯れが過ぎますなぁ
Smells good...
いい匂い
Get in.
入ってろ
It's not working...
効いてねぇ
Come, Hanki!
来い　伴器
Crap, I don't have a Sacred Tool right now!
やっべー　今神器いねぇんだった
Iki Hiyori!
壱岐ひより
ああ　来た
What the heck?!
You wanna fight?!
やって来い
You idiot!
バカ お前
Jungle... Savate!
ジャングルソバット
It-It worked!
き　効いてる
Touno-sama must've descended upon me!
蟷野さまが私に舞い降りてくださったんだわ
My lord, I will follow you for a lifetime!
マイロード　一生ついて行きます
We've lost it somehow...
何とかまいたな
Still, this girl saved me again.
にしてもこの女　また俺を助けた
We finally meet again, Yato-san.
やっと会えましたね　夜トさん
There are still a lot of things I wanted to ask you,
あなたにはまだ色々聞きたいことがあったんです
but you disappeared so suddenly.
なのに　すぐいなくなっちゃって
Don't dodge the subject this time and answer me properly!
今度こそ　はぐらかさないで答えてください
Did you notice that your soul has separated from your body?
お前さ
抜けてんぞ　魂
Eh?!
Eh!!
By the way, your body is hanging over there.
体はあそこに引っかかってる
That's me?!
あれ　私
Why?
どうして
Did I die?!
私死んでしまったの
It's not like you're dead.
死んだわけじゃねぇ
Your real body just fell asleep.
本体は眠ってるだけだ
My, my, what a lucky cat you are...
やれやれ
お前はなんっつう招き猫だよ
I will help you spread the fliers tomorrow, okay?
お母さん明日もチラシ配って探すから　ねえ
Don't worry, he will definitely turn up!
大丈夫　きっと見つかるわよ
Yes?
はい
Huh?
Milord!
ウエサマ
It's Milord!
ウエサマだ　ウエサマ
Milord!
My wish really came true!
本当にお願い叶っちゃった
Thank you, Yato!
ありがとう　夜ト
It smells good...
いい匂い
No way! Let me go, you pervert!
やだ
放して
変態
I'm not a pervert, I'm a god!
変態じゃねぇ　神だ
There you go, calling yourself a god again...
また神とか
That's right! My tail!
そうだ尻尾
Huh?
あれ　ない
It's gone!
What's going on here?
何 どういうこと
It was all a dream?
全部夢
It wasn't a dream, was it?
じゃないですよね
わ…私の体　どうなってしまったんですか
What happened to my body?
That accident must've been the cause.
事故が原因か
The world where humans currently live, and the Nirvana after that.
人が息づく此岸と
その対となる彼岸
In other words, you're existing between the two worlds right now.
いわばお前は　その二つの狭間にいる人間になった
The current world? Nirvana?
此岸と彼岸
Yeah.
The thing called Nirvana, in simpler terms, is the world after life.
彼岸ってのはまぁ　お前らの言葉で言う
あの世のことだ
You must've turned into an Ayakashi while still living as a human.
お前は生きながらにして　あやかしになったんだな
Ayakashi?
おやかし
Mankind's thoughts and desires that solidified, giving them form.
人の念が凝り固まって形を成したもの
They're the kind that possess people and do mischief.
人に取りついて悪さする類の奴らだ
Don't tell me that big frog earlier was also...
もしかしてさっきの大きな蛙も
Yup, it was an Ayakashi.
あやかしだ
No way, I'm the same as that thing?!
あれと一緒
No, it's slightly different.
いや　ちょっと違うな
Huh?
You're sort of like a half-baked one.
お前はもっと中途半端なもんだ
Um... I don't understand.
あの　よく分からないんですけど
You've become someone who will often drop his body.
あなたはよく体を落とす人になりました
So, how can I get it cured?
って　どうしたら治ります
Cured? I wonder about that...
治る　どうかな
Your body has already gained that kind of characteristic, give up.
お前はそういう体質になったんだ
諦めろ
No way!
そんな
That troubles me!
困ります　こんなの嫌です
Turn my body back to normal!
元に戻して
You're a god, aren't you, Yato-san? Help me!
夜トさんは神様なんでしょ
助けて
Money.
金
You charge money?!
お金取るんですか
Of course!
当たり前だ　ただで叶う願いなんかあるか
There's no such thing as a free wish.
It'll cost you this much.
これで手を打ってやる
Fifty thousand?!
五…五万　五十万
Five hundred thousand?!
I don't have that kind of money!
そんな大金
You fool.
愚かもの
I'm a god, you know.
俺は神だぞ
A five-yen coin is definitely the right amount for an offering!
賽銭は五円だと決ってんだろうが
Five? Huh? Um...
五っ
あっ　えっと
Your wish...
お前の願い
has been definitely heard!
確かに聞き届けた
Iki Hiyori, may fate smile upon you.
壱岐ひより
あなたにご縁が有らんことを
No matter your name, I'll call out to you.
君の名前 何があっても
必ず呼ぶから
You're the owner of a sharp, jagged heart.
君はぎざぎざハートの持ち主
Whatever might touch it gets hurt.
触れるものは何でも傷つけ
Staring sullenly at the world around you.
世界のすべてを睨み付けて
Those eyes say "I'm here."
その目は言うんだ
「僕はここにいる」
Someone's laughter stung.
誰かが笑ってた
だから引いたんだ その境界線
That's why you withdrew behind your borderline.
If that's the case, let me take you by the arm.
それなら
私はその手を引く
You're coming with me...
さぁ
連れてくから
If you can't say it, just hold my hand tightly.
言えないなら
この手を強く握って
Don't let it go.
離さないで
You're not alone any longer.
君はもう一人じゃないんだって
Just thought you should know.
知ってほしいんだよ
As a first step for the Yatogami Shrine, I propose we use a new shout for the Mikoshi!
夜ト神メジャー化計画の第一歩として
夜ト神輿のオリジナル掛け声制作を提案する
Can't we just use 'Wasshoi' as usual?
普通にわっしょいでいいじゃないですか
Not 'Wasshoi', but 'Yasshoi'!
わっしょいじゃなくて　やっしょいだ
Next time on Noragami: "Like Snow"
次回　ノラガミ
Next Episode
Like Snow
「雪のような」
"Yato-sama, Wasshoi!" becomes "Yasshoi", okay?
夜ト様わっしょいでやっしょいね